Hi ya sweetie.
They took the tube
out of his throat.
So now he's breathing
on his own.
He took a lot of damage
to his spleen.
They might have
to take it out.
Oh, my god.
I know.
I'm so scared.
Hey, listen,
listen.
This guy,
he's a tough kid.
If anybody could make it
through something like this,
it's christopher,
you hear me?
You got his holiness,
that's good.
He got shot too,
and survived.
Look!
Look what they did
to my son!
My son, those
sonsofbitches!
Easy, easy.
When you find him,
i want him to suffer,
you hear me, sil?
I want that motherfucker
in agony!
Don't worry, we'll
do the best we can.
Gismonte,
with a "g".
The kid who died,
right?
You never
heard of him?
No.
Well, him and his friend
matthew bevilaqua
ran around
with moltisanti.
Never saw him hanging out
with your buddy christopher?
I thought you wanted
to help your friend.
Hey.
Two days already,
i thought they were gonna
move him out of icu.
I think
he's getting better.
Good, you gotta
pray for him.
Hey, you gotta pray.
We are,
jesus.
Oh, i don't know
what i would do, uncle rich.
I love him
so much.
He's gonna make it.
I don't want
that fuck here.
I told him that.
He's full of
negative energies.
He said he'd only
come back here
if he had something
on matthew.
Start talking.
Back the fuck off.
Alright, what
do you got, rich?
The word is definitely
out on the fucking street
on this
bevilaqua kid.
Tommy biondi from otb
came up with a name,
a dealer named
quickie g.
He's been in the bing
a few times.
Or it might've been
this other prick, fast fatty.
I'm telling you
this won't take long.
I'll give this
bevilaqua kid five days
before somebody
brings his ass to us
to score points.
My brother
was in this hospital,
the bill was
75 pages long.
Eight dollars
for an aspirin.
So, did you hear about
ralph and mary rutaldo?
No, what happened?
You know ralphie has had
his brazilian goomar for years.
She's a dancer,
right?
She just gave birth
to ralph's baby,
a c- section.
Hey.
Why don't you try
and get some sleep?
Why?
Tomorrow's gonna be
another rough day,
that's why.
I don't think i'm gonna
sleep tonight.
Is this light
gonna bother you?
No.
Goodnight.
Tony?
I love you, tony.
I don't want
anybody getting hurt.
Not me,
not the kids,
not you.
Carmela, i can't do one of
these tearful things
till 5:00
in the morning tonight,
i just can't.
Not tonight.
Did you hear
about ralphie rutaldo?
What about him?
That brazilian
he keeps on the side?
Yeah?
She had a baby.
And christopher's
in the hospital,
this is on your mind now?
Maybe it
has to do with
the "ck one"
stinking up your shirt
last wednesday night.
It's over,
months ago!
Yeah, right.
"Yeah, right", what?
I told you i cut it off!
Listen tony, if you're gonna
keep doing what you do,
at the very least
i want you to get a vasectomy.
You want me
to do what?
Let's get real,
tony.
Do you have any idea
what a bastard child
would do
to this family?
You ever think about the shame
your children would feel?
You're putting us
all at risk.
I had her
tested for aids.
What do you
think i am?
Code blue icu 3,
code blue icu 3.
No, oh my god,
chrissy!
He's gonna die!
He'll be okay.
They said he was
gonna get better!
No!
No, let go
of me!
No, no!
Yeah.
What?
How is he?
His heart stopped.
They're working
their asses off on him.
Alright.
Well, we gotta
stay positive, right?
We gotta
give him that.
Positive vibes only.
Gentle and merciful
lord jesus,
i want to speak to you now
with an open heart,
with an honest heart.
Tonight i ask you
to take my sins
and the sins of my family
into your merciful heart.
We have chosen this life
in full awareness
of the consequences
of our sins.
I know that christopher's life
is in your hands...
and his fate is your will.
I ask you humbly
to spare him.
And if it is your will
to spare him,
i ask that you deliver him
from blindness
and grant him vision.
And through this visio
n may he see your love...
and gain the strength
to carry on in service
to your mercy.
In the name of the father,
the son,
and the holy spirit, amen.
Really, if i had
any reservations at all
i'd suggest
we move him right away.
But this is the best trauma unit
in the tri- state area.
I'm up on
all the ratings.
Thanks, hesh.
There's no
news yet.
Tony, it's
dr. Rueben.
Mr. Moltisanti suffered
cardiac and respiratory arrest
due to internal bleeding,
he was resuscitated.
The bleeding was
brought under control
and he's now
in stable condition.
What was the duration
of the arrest?
About a minute.
Is he stil
l intubated?
They're removing
the ventilator as we speak.
What the fuck you two
talking about?
The worst is over
but he was clinically dead
for about a minute.
Doctor, can i go in
and see him?
No, he's gonna
be in post- op
for about
four or five hours,
and then he asked
to speak to mr. Gualtieri.
Me?
He asked twice for
you and mr. Soprano.
Christopher.
Hey.
I'm sorry, t.
For what?
I know
you're mad at me.
What are you talking about?
I'm not mad at you.
Nobody's
mad at you.
I'm going to hell, t.
You're not going
anywhere but home.
I crossed over
to the other side.
You what?
I saw the tunnel
and the white light...
and i saw
my father in hell.
Get the fuck
out of here.
And the bouncer said
that i'd be there too
when my time comes.
What bouncer?
"The emerald piper",
that's our hell.
It's an irish bar
where it's st. Patrick's day
everyday forever.
Mikey palmice
and brendan filone
were there too.
They were friends.
Those two guys
hated each other.
You gotta relax,
you just need some rest.
They're friends now.
They were playing dice
with two roman soldiers
and a bunch
of the irish guys.
Doesn't make sense.
The irish, they were
winning every roll.
And then mikey gave me
a message for both of you.
A message?
Yeah.
Yeah, he said...
"tell tony and paulie,
3:00."
3:00?
This fucking morphine drip
, i don't think it's working.
I don't feel
a fucking thing.
You gotta be
careful with that.
That was
all he said?
Who?
Mikey,
"3:00"?
Yeah.
What was
he wearing?
C'mon, let's go,
he needs his rest.
He had on a gangster suit,
pinstripe.
Old fashioned style.
Hey...
that was a dream.
Forget about it,
okay?
We're gonna
take you home soon.
Do they know this kid
likes his chemistry set
a little too much?
He's in pain,
what the fuck else
are they gonna do?
What time
was mikey hit?
How the fuck
do i know?
You were there,
weren't you?
It was
in the morning, right?
11:00, 10:00?
Alright, so i cheat--
i used to cheat.
I'm not getting spayed,
end of subject.
You brought up
the vasectomy,
now you don't
want to talk about it.
You asked me
what was going on.
I saw in the news
about a gangland shooting.
Yeah.
Is that your nephew christophe
that you've spoken of before?
In the papers they said
he was in critical condition.
He's gonna be fine.
Have they found the person
that shot him yet?
No...
have you?
I'm not trying to pry into
that part of your life.
I know our deal.
But i've heard you say before
that you love this young man.
Christopher was...
clinically dead
for about a minute.
He thinks he had one of those
near death experiences.
Says he visited hell.
And they told him
he'd be back permanent.
Who's "they"?
It's bullshit,
it was a dream,
combined with
the morphine.
But now he thinks he's gonna
go to hell when he dies.
He's all fucked up
over it.
Do you think
he'll go to hell?
No.
He's not the type
that deserves hell.
Who do you
think does?
The worst people.
The twisted
and demented psychos
who kill people
for pleasure.
The cannibals,
the degenerate bastards
that molest and
torture little kids.
They kill babies.
The hitlers,
the pol pots.
Those are the evil fucks
that deserve to die.
Not my nephew.
What about you?
What?
Hell?
You been
listening to me?
No...
for the same reasons.
We're soldiers.
Soldiers don't
go to hell.
It's war.
Soldiers,
they kill other soldiers.
We're in a situation
where everybody involved
knows the stakes.
And if you're gonna
accept those stakes...
you gotta
do certain things.
It's business,
we're soldiers.
We follow codes...
orders.
So does that justify
everything that you do?
Excuse me,
let me tell you something.
When america opened
the floodgates
and let all us
italians in,
what do you think
they were doing it for?
Because they were trying
to save us from poverty?
No, they did it
because they needed us.
They needed us
to build their cities
and dig their subways
and to
make'em richer.
The carnegies
and the rockefellers,
they needed worker bees
and there we were.
But some of us didn't want
to swarm around their hive
and lose who we were.
We wanted
to stay italian
and preserve the things
that meant something to us.
Honor, and family,
and loyalty.
And some of us wanted
a piece of the action.
We weren't educate
d like the americans.
But we had the balls
to take what we wanted.
Those other fucks,
those other...
the j. P. Morgans,
they were crooks
and killers too,
but that was
a business, right?
The american way.
That might
all be true.
But what do
poor italian immigrants
have to do with you
and what happens every morning
you step out of bed?
What the fuck is this
all of a sudden?
I'm just asking
a question.
Oh, so you're taking
a stand here now.
Huh? You pick here
to make a stand?
After all this time,
telling me that
nothing's my fault
because of
poor parenting.
You pick now to act like
betsy- fucking- ross!
When my nephew's
in the fucking hospital!
He might not
get out!
What, what
3 o'clock again?
Quiet.
My wind chimes?
Sorry, hon.
Don't wake up
my kids, paulie.
Motherfucker.
Baby, you gotta
relax your thoughts.
Whatever christopher saw,
you can't take it personal.
Christopher's
a troubled kid.
Who knows
what's in his heart?
Come.
You're right.
I need to relax
with this.
Let me help you.
That is so weird.
What the fuck
you saying?
3:00?
Kenny and i were supposed
to be married at 1:00
in the fountainbleu room
at the roman gardens.
Mikey and jo- jo had
the bella vista room
booked for 3:00.
But the bella vista room
is smaller and has no windows.
A week
before the wedding
mikey saw the bella vista room
and flipped out!
He almost killed
the events manager.
So mikey and jo- jo
got the fountainbleu
and kenny and me wound up
in the bella vista room
at 3:00.
Fuck.
Just trying to
tidy up the place.
Go back to sleep.
Tidying up?
How you doing?
I'm doing.
I'll tell ya...
i'm still baffled by
this 3:00 thing though.
I wish i had
more for you, paulie,
but that's all he said.
Let me ask you
a question.
Yeah?
That bouncer
that sent you back,
did he have horns
on his head?
No.
He was just some
big irish goon
in old fashioned clothes.
Did anybody there
have horns
or buds for horns,
those goat bumps?
Paulie, it was
fucking hell, okay?
My father said he looses
every hand of cards he plays.
And every night
at midnight
they whack him the same way
he was whacked in life
and it's painful,
night after night.
Does that sound like
fucking heaven to you?
Was it hot?
Yeah...
i don't know.
What the fuck?
The heat would've been
the first thing you noticed.
Hell is hot.
That's never been
disputed by anybody.
You didn't
go to hell.
You went to purgatory,
my friend.
I forgot
all about purgatory.
Purgatory,
a little detour
on the way to paradise.
How long you think
we gotta stay there?
That's different
for everybody.
You add up all
your mortal sins,
multiply that number
by 50,
then you add up
all your venial sins
and multiply that
by 25.
You add them together,
and that's your sentence.
I figure i'm gonna have to do
about 6, 000 years
before i get
accepted into heaven.
And 6, 000 years is nothing
in eternity terms.
I could do that
standing on my head.
It's like a couple
of days here.
Was i insensitive?
And perhaps,
did i do it deliberately?
Do i hate him?
How often are you
taking the ativan?
Almost every night.
And when else?
Sunday afternoon
i took one.
There's another thing,
i've...
i've been drinking...
alone.
I'm glad
you're telling me.
Part of it is that
i'm afraid.
I've told him
my son is at bard.
Why did you agree to
continue working with him?
I took him back
because i felt it was
a professional
and ethical responsibility
to do so.
Jennifer, i'm not
challenging your ability
or professionalism
, or even your ethics.
Then what are you
challenging?
What you hope to
achieve with this man.
What do you hope
to achieve with me?
No, that's a--
a facile analogy.
I'm living in a moral
never never land
with this patient.
Not wanting to judge,
but to treat.
But now...
i've judged.
I took a position, goddamnit,
and i'm scared.
I feel for you.
You're late.
Does that
go on my record?
I'm talking about
common courtesy here.
I got a life
outside of this too.
Lucky you.
So, what
do you got?
I think he knows.
Knows what?
Or at least suspects.
Who, what?
What are you talking about?
He's been looking
at me different,
these glances.
Glances?
We had sandwiches brought in
the other night,
four with ham, salami,
cappicola,
one eggplant, and the other
with tomato and mozzarella.
Yeah, okay.
That's six total,
there were only five of us.
But tony said
he ordered the eggplant,
but i did,
and i know
for certain he ordered
the tomato/mozzarella.
Maybe he forgot.
No, no,
he never forgets.
So, what's
the bottom line?
He let me eat the eggplant
and he took the tomato.
But there was
a moment.
A glance.
Yeah,
a fucking glance!
This is simple and
i'm gonna help you out here.
You gotta keep in mind
that you're the one
who's different now.
You're the one seeing
through different eyes.
You're the one
with the new attitude.
I know the man
and i see he's the one
who's different with me.
The odds
don't favor it.
Either way
it doesn't matter.
To you.
I wasn't the one
selling heroin, okay?
And i wasn't the one
who got pinned for it.
So what do i do?
What do you do?
You do everything
you can do do.
Do what you do to a girl
that you want to fuck.
Make him love you.
I'll be back first thing
in the morning.
What do you want
for breakfast?
You don't wake up
till lunch, ma.
Tomorrow i'll get up
early, alright?
How about the peppers and eggs
on the round bread?
That sound
s great, ma.
Do you need
more time alone, jo?
No, i'm ready.
Okay, chris.
Bye, ma.
If you want to sleep, it's okay,
i brought a book.
No, i just got up
ten minutes ago.
The painkillers
aren't helping?
No, they're pretty
fucking good.
I want to tell you something,
christopher.
The other night
when your heart stopped...
i walked the hall
to an empty room
and i prayed to jesus
to spare you.
And that
if he would spare you
i asked that
he grant you vision.
Sight.
So that you can see
the way to christ clearly.
Yeah, so?
And he did
spare you.
And you saw,
christopher.
You saw something,
something that none of us
have ever seen.
So what did
he say to you?
Who?
Jesus.
I didn't see jesus.
Tony said that
you saw jesus smiling
and he took you to see
your father in heaven
and then he said
it wasn't your time.
I was in hell,
carmela.
You what?
My father
was in hell
and they said that's where
i'd go when it's my time.
Maybe it was purgatory,
but i don't know.
Then you have to look
at this experience
as an opportunity
to repent...
to change your heart...
to start to walk in
the light of the lord.
You were blessed
by this, christopher.
with a second chance.
I don't know,
carmela.
Well, i do know.
And i am gonna pray
like i did the other night
and i'm gonna pray
every day from now on.
It is not too late for you,
christopher...
if you pray.
Will you pray?
You just have to
follow me.
In the name of the father,
the son,
and the holy spirit.
How was he?
Fine.
The same.
Is there
any news?
No.
So, what?
We're not talking now?
I said what i had
to say, tony.
If you can't
be honest with me,
at least have the balls
to be honest with yourself.
Oh, i got balls.
And as long as i do,
they will remain intact.
If you don't have faith in me,
it's up to you.
You gotta prove it
to yourself first, tony.
To yourself
and god.
You and god,
carmela.
You're only religious
when it suits you.
What is that
supposed to mean?
Come here.
No, no, what is that
supposed to mean?
The pope doesn't even
believe in trojans
and you want me
to get snipped.
Isn't that a little
hypocritical?
Look, tony, i'm thinking o
f my family first, that's all.
Whatever's down here
is god's creation.
Isn't it a sin to undo
the good work he's done?
You should know,
you made a living of it.
You're un- fucking- believable,
you know that?
Look what i made
that living for, hmm?
What the fuck
you doing?
You had dinner
an hour ago.
What the fuck are you
doing to yourself?
Tony,
leave him alone.
I'm supposed to get a vasectomy
when this is my male heir?
Look at him.
Tony, come back here
and apologize!
You're draggin'
me to hell!
What's the matter,
what's the matter?
You're draggin'
me to hell!
Paulie, paulie,
you had
a nightmare, honey.
Mama, somebody was screaming,
i'm scared.
I know, honey,
it's okay, it's okay.
Uncle paulie
had a bad dream.
Mommy!
Come here,
baby.
It's alright,
it's alright.
It's okay,
sweetheart.
I'm putting them
to bed.
Then i'm going home
to sleep.
I don't need to keep
everyone up with this.
C'mon,
let's go to sleep.
Come talk to me.
How much can you
believe in dreams?
Wait, wrong.
Christopher did not
have a dream.
I dream,
i'd make my peace.
He was dead.
Science said he was dead,
science.
You need to
talk to someone
who deals with this kind
of thing professionally.
What kind of thing?
He's in
new york, paulie,
in nyack.
His name is cullen,
he's a psychic.
A psychic, get the fuck
out of here.
He's famous for contacting
dead relatives for people.
He contacted
my dead friend ronnie.
Remember ronnie
with the arm?
Yeah.
He knew all about
the fingers at the elbow
and i didn't
even tell him.
He said,
"johnnie is here."
And i told him
i didn't know any johnnie's,
but then he said,"well, one arm
is shorter than the other.
Does that mean
anything to you?"
Ronnie,
it was ronnie.
Jesus,
fucking creep show.
You got nothing to lose
except the nightmares.
What's up?
Paulie around?
No.
Sil?
What the fuck, i'm here,
you talk to me.
You got something?
You better
remember me, man.
Yeah, i will,
now, you got something?
Alright.
Hacklebarney
state park.
You know where that
"george washington
slept- here- house" is?
Up that road there
is a gray house.
Bevilaqua's there?
20 bucks, baby.
Are you telling me
that's who you are
or that's who he is?
I see.
Right.
The spirit put
him on hold.
Do you take the name
gregory?
My father.
I understand now.
You're gregory,
this is your son.
Is your name
daniel?
Yes.
'Cause i got this image of
daniel in the lion's den.
He says
you found his body.
Oh, my god.
He's sorry.
He knows
how traumatic that was.
He couldn't
take the pain anymore.
Gregory, i'm sorry,
could you repeat that?
He wants you to know
that he was there with you.
And that you
should move on.
Yes, go ahead.
What's
the problem?
What the hell's
the matter?
Please, go on.
He can't hurt you,
you don't have to be afraid.
I understand, yes.
I feel your anger.
Who the fuck
are you talking to?
Charles.
Yes, yes,
you have a son.
You're wit
h your son?
What the fuck?
I don't got no kids.
Oh, sonny.
Pagano?
Kind spirit,
is your name sonny?
Charles pagano.
How the fuck
do you know that?
He says
he was your first.
But i feel many more.
Hey!
That one's
laughing.
Poison ivy?
He wants to know
if it still itches.
Don't fuck with me,
who you been talking to?
I'm afraid i'm gonna have to
ask you to leave.
Why?
What the fuck
are they saying?
You really want me
to say it?
Fuck you
and this bullshit.
That's what this is,
you know.
Satanic black magic,
sick shit!
I'm asking you
to leave, sir.
Yeah?
Fucking queers!
When i made my appointment
, i gave the name ted hughes.
Did you call
from your house?
I'm not a moron, t.
I knew this might
be a scam.
So i called him
from a pathmark.
There's
no denying it.
I'm dragging a bunch of
fucking ghouls around with me
and mikey's
their fucking ringleader.
Alright...
paulie...
think about it.
You whacked a bunch of
heavy hitters in your time,
now, you think they're gonna
all join together
and follow
that prick mikey?
How can you
just sit there?
He warned you
about 3:00 too.
I don't believe
any of this shit.
It doesn't mean
a fucking thing to me.
I was ready to write
the whole thing off
until this psychic mentioned
little sonny pagano.
But, that?
I don't know.
I did this guy
over 30 years ago, t.
How the fuck
did he know that?
Does he know where
matt bevilaqua is?
Did you ask the fucking
ghostbuster that?
'Cause we're out there
breaking our ass
trying to find this kid,
and you're up there
fucking around in nyack.
He deals only
with the dead.
You eat steak?
What the fuck
you talking about?
If you were in india,
you would go to hell for that.
I'm not in india,
what do i give a fuck?
That's what i'm trying
to tell you.
None of this shit
means a goddamn thing.
I'm not hungry.
You mind if i sit here
while i eat?
I'm sorry for talking to you
the way i did.
It's okay.
No...
it's not.
I was wrong.
And i hope you know
i didn't mean it.
I said it'cause
all the anger and frustration
of the last few days
built up inside me and exploded.
There's no excuse
for that.
I gotta learn to
control my emotions
around the people i love.
I think
you're the same way.
I think,
your feelings,
you keep'em inside,
and you and me,
we react without thinking.
That's why i get mad at you,
i see myself in you.
I couldn't ask
for a better son, a. J.
And i mean that.
Thanks.
Want a piece of pizza?
Here.
Pussy's
on the phone.
He says
it's urgent.
I been calling you all
over the fucking place.
I'll be
right there.
What's going on?
Nothing.
He's way the fuck out
near morristown,
in hacklebarney
state park.
Over by that "george washington
slept- here- house"?
Yeah.
Give me one.
You don't
have to do this.
Furio and me
are on it.
I want to do this.
Good.
Cut furio loose.
Three's a crowd.
Why don't you just
take it easy?
We just want
to talk to you.
That's all.
It wasn't me,
it was sean,
just sean.
You're shaking.
You're gonna fucking kill me
for something i didn't do.
Don't you think we could've
killed you already,
if we
wanted you dead.
Relax.
We just want
to talk to you.
Tony, it was sean!
You got to believe me,
it was sean, he got nuts!
He said we're being pissed on
and disrespected
and that we should
score points with richie.
But i told him rome wasn't
built in one day!
Anything tony, i'll tell you
anything you want to know.
What did
richie say?
It nothing to do with richie,
he didn't ask for it.
He got mad
when i told him.
Sean did it on spec.
Alright.
Come here.
Come here,
c'mon.
Are you sure nobody else
was involved?
Take a minute,
think it over.
It was sea
n all the way.
Alright.
You're a good kid.
I'm thirsty.
See if we got
something to drink.
What can
i get you?
You want a fanta,
something like that?
How is that?
I mean, you sure
you want a diet drink?
You don't want something
with some sugar in it?
There's only diet.
It's good.
You finished?
Thank you, t.
'Cause that
sugarless motherfucker,
it's the last fucking drink
you're ever gonna have.
I swear to god,
mommy!
Mommy, please, tony,
please!
23 years of donations
to your parish
and this is what
this guy sees hanging over me?
You should've never gone
to a psychic.
It's divination,
it's the devil.
They're completely
unsanctioned by the church.
Psychics are
heretics and thieves
who practice witchcraft.
There's no validity
to anything he told you.
Your problem's
a spiritual matter.
Maybe.
But irregardless,
i should've had immunity
to all of this shit.
I should've been covered
by my donations.
When the organ needed
a reed job who was there?
When the priest
and the alter boys
needed new whites,
who picked up
the tab?
You should've
come to me first
and none of this
would've happened.
But don't worry, paul,
i'm here.
I can help you.
It's too late.
You've been slacking off on me
and you left me unprotected.
I'm cutting you off
for good.
You ain't never gonna see
another dime from me.
A rich man and a poor man
got the same wedding anniversary
and every year they meet
on madison avenue
when their shopping
for their wives.
So the poor man
says to the rich man,
"what'd you buy
your wife this year?"
He says,"i got her
a huge diamond ring
and a brand new
mercedes."
Poor man says,"what'd you
get her both for?"
Rich man says,
"if she don't
like the diamond ring
she can bring it back
in the mercedes
and still be happy."
Rich man says
to the poor man,
"what'd you get
your wife this year?"
He says, i got her
a pair of slippers and dildo."
Rich man says,"what'd you
get her a pair of slippers
and a dildo for?"
And the poor man says,
"she don't like the slippers
she can go fuck herself."
Can i get
another heineken?
Remember the first time
you brought me here?
Yeah,
i remember.
Popped my cherry
that night.
Yeah, seems like
old times.
Puss.
You believe in god?
Yeah, i do, ton',
absolutely.
Works in very mysterious ways
his wonders to perform,
but no doubt,
he's been
very good to me.
Salut.
Hi.
Hey.
How you doing?
Fine.
You?
Good.
Yeah?
I've been thinking...
what?
I'll do it.
You'll do what?
Snip- snip.
I don't want you
to do it, tony.
No, you want me
to do it.
And now
i want to do it.
So...
we'll do it.
I started thinking...
meadow is
leaving soon...
and i may want to
have another baby.
Maybe.
What, are you trying
to drive me fucking crazy?
What's behind
all this?
Ralphie rutald
o and his goomar,
then the vasectomy
, then no vasectomy,
and now this, huh?
Now you don't
want me cut?
Tony...
all i want
is you.
That's all
i have ever wanted.
And i want you to be true
and to be mine.
I want you
to not cheat.
I will be true, carm,
from now on--
tony, please.
If you're not gonna
believe me, then fine.
What can i do?
I don't know.
Prove it to me.
Captions copyright 2000
home box office